Paryush Jain

paryushjain@gmail.com

+91 9970180900 Hyderabad, Telangana. www.paryushjain.github.io https://www.linkedin.com/in/paryushjain/ Java, Spring Boot, Microservices

Summary of Qualifications

- 2+ years of professional experience in Java, Microservices, Spring Boot, MySQL, PCF & Angular.
- As a part of the assignments, I have been in Requirement Analysis, Design, Development & Unit Testing.
- Sound knowledge of SDLC and worked with Agile Methodology and Scrum Framework.

Technical Synopsis

Programming & Scripting Languages:	Java, HTML, CSS, XML
Frameworks:	Spring Boot, Angular, jQuery, Scrum/Agile
Version Control & Tracking Tools: GitHub, Jira	
Database:	MySQL, IBM DB2, Microsoft SQL Server
IDE & Other Tools:	STS, Jenkins, Swagger, Soap UI, Sonar Cube, PCF, IBM ODM, Maven

Project Experience

Project Name: Claims Adjudication System		Duration: Jan 2018 - Present	
Firm: Deloitte			
Role	Software Developer		
Client	Healthcare		
Technology Stack	Sprint Boot, Microservices, Angular 5, Git Hub, Jenkins, Jira, Sonar, IBM ODM, PCF		
Project Abstract	Project aims to replace 30 years legacy system developed in Mainframe to rebuilt as Cloud based application using Microservices architecture and other latest technologies.		
Responsibilities	 Involved in development, requirement analysis, designing and defect fixing. Rules Design using Rules Designer IBM ODM. Testing using Junit, Mockito and Swagger. 		

Project Name: Online Exa Firm: CodeWizards Tecl		Duration: Jul 2017 – Dec 2017	
Role	Full Stack Developer(Intern)		
Client	CodeWizards Tech		
Technology Stack	PHP, HTML, CSS, MYSQL, GitHub		
Project Abstract	Project aims to develop online exam portal for conducting online test which was supposed to be used for recruitment purposes.		
Responsibilities	 Involved in all phases of Software Development Life Cycle. Provided solution for conducting online exams. 		

Professional Experience

Deloitte USI Pvt Ltd, Hyderabad Business Technology Analyst		Dec 2017 – Present	
InfoCepts, Nagpur	MicroStrategy Developer (Intern) June 2016 – S		
CodeWizards Tech, Nagpur	PHP Developer (Intern)	July 2017 – Dec, 2017	

Recognitions and Certifications

Java	Oracle Certified Associate Java SE8 Certified Programmer I	
Java	Oracle Certified Professional Java SE8 Certified Programmer II	
Spot Award	For presenting excellent demo to the Client	
Applause Award	For excellent performance through out the year 2019.	
Best BI project award	InfoCepts Business Intelligence Project Award	

Educational Qualification

Yeshwantrao Chavan College of Engineering, Nagpur	B.E. (Computer Technology - 87%)	2013-17
VMV College, Nagpur	12 th (81%)	2012-13
Prerna Convent, Nagpur	10 th (89%)	2010-11